Guide to the Dorothy Eisler Collection ARS.0057
Archive of Recorded Sound
Dorothy Eisler Collection
1964-1970
ARS.0057
Eisler, Dorothy
1 box 32 open reel tapes (twenty-four 10" open reel tapes; eight 5" open reel tapes)
Archive of Recorded Sound
The Dorothy Eisler Collection consists of live recordings of classical music from approximately 1964 to 1970.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
The Dorothy Eisler Collection consists of 32 open reel tapes of symphonies and operas, recorded from live broadcasts on Radio Vienna, KPEN, and elsewhere, from approximately 1964 to 1970. Works by Mozart, Mahler, Wagner, Strauss, Bruckner, and Brahms are featured, among many others. Three tapes are devoted to the Vienna Festival of 1970. Tapes are minimally annotated, and no complete list of contents exists as of yet.
Indexing Terms
Live sound recordings; Operas; Radio programs; Symphonies
- 1. Live recordings of symphonies and operas (titles from tape boxes)
  - Festwochenkonzert- Vienna, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Vienna Festival - Ozawa - Brahms Second Symphony, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Vienna Festival - Opening Concert - Karl Bohm, Vienna Philharmonic - Bruckner Symphony No.8, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Vienna Festival - Oistrak - Tchaikovsky Violin Concerto, Symphony No.6, Pathetique, 1970-05-27 (Box 1)
  - Das Glueck Einer Nacht, Operette - Kickinger (Box 1)
  - Pariser Leben - Jacques Offenbach (Box 1)
  - Wiener Brut - Greek Theater, Los Angeles, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Die Dollarprinzessin - Fall (Box 1)
  - Zigeunerbaron - Strauss (Box 1)
  - Die Rose Von Stambul - Leo Fall (Box 1)
  - Jamaican Rhumba - Benjamin - Isaac Stern CSO, KPEN stereo broadcast (Box 1)
  - Wagner- Meistersinger - Metropolitan Opera (Box 1)
  - Wagner- Meistersinger end, Lohengrin #1 - Metropolitan Opera (Box 1)
  - In Weissen Rossel (Box 1)
  - Alfred Piccaver Sings (Box 1)
  - Orson Welles - War of the Worlds - KPEN, 1964-06-17 (Box 1)
  - Viennese Philharmonic - Mahler/Bruckner (Box 1)
  - Flotov - Martha (Box 1)
  - Mozart - Symphony Es Dur.KV 543 (Box 1)
  - Carmina Burana - Choir Vienna (Box 1)
  - Aida - Radio Vienna - Nielson/Corelli/Mehta (Box 1)
  - Don Pasquale - Vienna State Opera - Vienna Radio (Box 1)
  - Verdi - Falstaff (Box 1)
  - Wiener Festwoche Klemperer, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Strauss - Don Juan - Szell, Berlin Philharmonic - Radio Vienna (Box 1)
  - Schumann - Symphony No.2 - Szell, Berlin Philharmonic - Radio Vienna (Box 1)
  - Ein Walzertraum (Box 1)
  - Operreten Konzert - Radio Vienna (Box 1)
  - Soloisten, Kenner, Spezialisten - Radio Vienna (Box 1)
  - Robert Stol Dirigiert (Box 1)
  - Operettenausschnitte From Orf No.1 (Box 1)
  - Mahler - Symphony No.3 - Barbirolli, Berlin Philharmonic, Lucretia West - Radio Vienna (Box 1)